Jen-Chieh Shen

Email: jenchieh94@gmail.com Website: www.jcs-profile.com

ABOUT

I am a well-rounded software engineer/architect expert on tool invention and deep-in automation, currently focusing on backend infrastructure. My previous education as a game programmer gave me solid programming knowledge regarding creating things from scratch. e.g. Graphic Rendering, UI, Scripting Engine, Networking, etc.

KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

- · Designing system architecture.
- Analyzing, troubleshooting, optimizing systems.
- Business analysis, requirement analysis.
- Linux administration, maintenance, automation.
- Technical writing.
- Languages: English, Chinese.

TOOLS AND TECHNOLOGIES (SAMPLED)

- Languages: C, C++, C#, Java, JavaScript, Elisp, Python, Lua, Rust...
- Database: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB...
- Web/network frameworks: Netty, MINA, Express.js, ws, DRF...
- Infrastructure: AWS, Digital Ocean, Docker...
- Tools: Emacs, Vim, Git, Perforce, Jenkins...

WORK EXPERIENCE

Unity Developer (Contract)

Apr., 2020 - May, 2022

Novaby - Seattle, Washington, United States

- Provide full UI elements for already built Augmented Reality application.
- Communicate and work with upstream software engineer for two ends integration.
- Analyze and consult CEO and her clients for making technical decisions.
- Build framework/tools to increase productivity by maximum 80 percents

Senior Unity Engineer

May, 2020 - Jan, 2021

ultragbye - Taipei, Taiwan

- Provide full application interaction, network interface/module and tool programming.
- Create a mini/test server using NodeJS for standardized the web server side API content.
- Manage to create bluetooth connection from Mono C# to each mobile platforms and implements to Linux Kernel (Debian) using Raspberry Pi as peripheral device.

Cocos Software Engineer (Consultant)

Dec, 2019 – Mar, 2020

WISBET Digital Entertainment Developing Co. Ltd - Taipei, Taiwan

- Communicate with the high-end developers in Cocos Creator community to improve UI/UX.
- Advise team's technical directors to improve the maintainability of all the existing projects.
- Resolve technical issues for designers, artists, and producers.
- Review and revise code to enhance the code coverage and improve readability.
- Make bug reports and issue tracking documents then propose better solutions.
- Create Cocos Creator's scripting framework base on it's game engine principle.

Chief Technology Officer

Game Barley - Taipei, Taiwan

- Build and design both game client and server's software structure.
- Manage a group of software engineers and give reasonable tasks.
- Communicate with CEO and Art Lead in non-technical way and discuss products' tendency.
- Give code review and discuss to invent new custom game algorithms.
- Analyze technical risks and arrange project's progress.

Server Software Engineer

Sep, 2018 - May, 2019

T-Nexus - San Francisco Bay Area

- Provide login server web API using Express.js in the Node JS environment.
- Design schema for the login server using mongoose built on top of the MongoDB.
- Build automated program to run the server on to the AWS using shell script.
- Install and setup Node JS environment on AWS EC2 instance running on Ubuntu.
- Communicate with client engineers to implement HTTP request model to the client using Unity C#.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Games presented in Game Developer Conferences (GDC)

GDC at San Francisco Bay Area

GDC 2015

- "Archers Duel" two player fighting game.
- "Cardinal" visual novel game.

GDC 2017

"Might & Blade" – Diablo like action RPG.

GDC 2018

"Sugar Sleuths" – players discover clues to uncover who stole the camp's Master Stash of candy.

Games presented in E3 College Game Competition

Hosted by Entertainment Software Association (ESA), USA

E3 CGC 2018

"Sugar Sleuths" - has been selected to represent our school Academy of Art University

EDUCATION

Academy of Art University, San Francisco, CA Bachelor of Fine Arts - BFA, Game Development

Sep, 2012 - Dec, 2017